Timothy LaRoy

703.909.5511

https://krombopulos.github.io/portfolic Timlaroy93@gmail.com

About Me

Motivated and skilled Control Systems Technician with 1 year of experience in designing, implementing, and maintaining control systems for various industrial processes. Adept at troubleshooting and optimizing control systems to ensure efficient and reliable operations. Seeking a challenging position to contribute technical expertise and enhance organizational efficiency.

Skills

- Control Systems Design and Implementation
- PLC Programming (e.g., Allen-Bradley, Siemens)
- HMI Design and Configuration
- Process Optimization
- Troubleshooting and Maintenance
- Instrumentation and Calibration
- Technical Documentation
- Team Collaboration and Communication
- Computer coding in Java and Python
- Data Analysis and Machine Learning
- IT Support

Employment History

Control Systems Technician (Jun 2023 - Current)

JLL - Sparrow's Point, MD

- Leads and assists in repair and maintenance of control systems on robotics, packaging, and conveyance equipment
- Develops training materials for safety and PLC systems
- Develops database tools and spreadsheets for optimization of reporting and dataflow
- Completed over 800 work orders spanning over 1800 labor hours

Material Handling Technician II (Dec 2022 - Jun 2023)

JLL - Sparrow's Point, MD

- Performed maintenance and inspections on mechanical conveyance, packing equipment, and robotic machinery
- Provided client facing troubleshooting and resolution during operational runtime

Helicopter Crewman & Tech (Oct 2012 - Oct 2017)

United States Marine Corps

- Responsible for 40+ Marines, 4 aircraft, and a multi-million dollar account
- Organized daily operations for squadron and oversaw the technical training of the unit leading to highest squadron readiness in all of Marine Corps
- Performed maintenance and inspections as Quality Assurance representative on all aircraft

Education

M.S. - Applied Exercise Science 2020

Concordia University - Chicago

B.S. - Sports and Health Science 2018 - 2019

American Military University

B.S. - Computer Science estimated 2024

Western Governors University

Certifications

- Google Data Analytics and IT Support Specializations
- Java and Python Programming Specializations